Evan Derby

http://www.polyov.com

2834 Shoshone Trail. Lafayette, CO. 80026.

Phone: (303)-408-6773 | Email: somekidwithhtml@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a developer who has a wide range of interests and experience- both inside and outside of development.

Having knowledge of lots of other areas is important to creating a well-rounded product, not just on a code level, but also on an outward facing user level. Experience in visual and dramatic arts informs me on how users view and react to a product. Knowledge of computer and natural sciences hint on how to create well structured and efficient systems. And history with a wide variety of tools and platforms enable to me to always pick the best option for the job at hand. If I don't know your toolset, I've been a newbie to so many other things that a transition to something else is a piece of cake.

On my own, I'm adaptive, but when I'm set into the structure and environment of your team, I'm focused, precise, and detail-oriented, in all aspects of design.

I'm like a swiss army knife that also happens to include a 3D printer.

Work Experience

- August 2015-Present: **Mountain's Edge Fitness**: *Front Desk Attendant* Boulder, CO. Responsible for the front desk at a local fitness club. I greet members, clean mirrors, and give tours to prospective members. I also DJ the music in the weight room.
- Summer 2013, 2014: **Coshx Labs**: *Intern, Front-End Software Developer-* Boulder, CO. Responsible for fixing bugs and adding features on the company's website. Also created iOS apps and Ruby on Rails websites as independent projects. http://coshx.com
- Summer 2013: University of Colorado Boulder, Chemical Engineering Department: *Intern*.
 - Responsible for maintaining an experimental setup testing gas diaphragms and attending research meetings.
- Summer 2014: Anson Adams: Web Designer Boulder, CO.
 Created a portfolio website for independent artist and animator Anson Adams.
 Responsible for adapting design of website provided to code.
 http://www.ansonadams.net.
- Summer 2014: **Metalithic Ironworks**: *Web Designer, Graphic Designer* Arvada, CO. Created a website for fabrication company Metalithic Ironworks, based in Arvada, CO.

- Designed company logo and website visuals. Responsible for taking previous website and adapting it to new system. http://arvadawelding.com
- 2013: **High Country Hydrology**: *Application Developer* Boulder, CO. Tasked with developing an Android application used for converting water flow rate units.

Additional Projects

- 2011-2015: **Fairview High School Website**: *Fairview High School* Boulder, CO. Part of a team of students responsible for maintaining Fairview High School's website, written in Ruby on Rails. http://fairviewhs.org
- 2015-2016: Fairview High School Royal Banner Website: Fairview High School-Boulder, CO.
 - Re-wrote, from the ground up, the website of the school's newspaper, the Royal Banner. Now responsible for maintaining and adding new features. Also writing stories and movie reviews as a staff reporter. http://fhsroyalbanner.com
- 2016: Hello LA!: Hack @ Brown Providence, RI
 Attended Hack @ Brown 2016 at Brown University. Part of a team that developed "Hello LA" in less than 24 hours. Wrote the backend of the website and most of the front end. "Hello LA" won the Best User Experience Award.
- 2016: **Polyov** Boulder, CO.

 Created a portfolio website to showcase my design abilities and previous created works.

 Also hosts a blog.
- 2014-2016: **Fairview High School Emergency Response Team**: *Fairview High School* Boulder, CO.
 - Part of a team trained in First Aid, responsible for caring for students in emergency situations.
- Summer 2013: JARVIS: Coshx Labs- Boulder, CO.
 As part of the company's hackathon, designed a simple system for interpreting commands using Natural Language Processing libraries in Python and Javascript.
- 2012: Dijkstra's Algorithm
 - Used Javascript to an implementation of Dijkstra's Algorithm, a mathematical algorithm used to determine the shortest path between nodes on an undirected, weighted line graph. http://github.com/skwh/SKWDA
- 2013: Asteroids.js
 - Used Javascript and the HTML5 Canvas API to create a Javascript based version of Asteroids, an old arcade game.
- 2015-2016: Colorado Junior Classical League Officer- Colorado.
 Served as Parliamentarian with the Colorado Junior Classical League. Responsible for coordinating events and officer elections within the CoJCL.

Education

• University of Denver: **BS Computer Science**, 2020

Honors and Awards

- 2012: Fairview High School: Science Student of the Year
 Awarded for academic excellence in the science department at Fairview High School.
- 2014, 2015: Fairview High School: National Lation Examination, Magna Cum Laude Awarded for excellent performance on the National Latin Examination.
- 2015: Fairview High School: National Junior Classical League, Magna Cum Laude Awarded for excellent performance on tests relating to classical civilizations as part of the Colorado Junior Classics Convention.

Skill Set

- Ruby on Rails
- Javascript & jQuery
- UI / UX Design
- HTML5 & CSS3
- Linux-based development
- Objective-C and Xcode development
- Java